I'm sorry, Steve.
I’m truly sorry.
对不起，Steve，实在对不起！
I’m not sorry. I am not sorry.
Don't be sorry. Never be sorry.
没有，我没有对不起他
没必要对他说抱歉，这辈子都不会！
-Wake up!
起来了！起来了！
-Happy birthday!
生日快乐！生日快乐！
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you. Give us a snuggle.
Give us a kiss, sweetheart.
谢谢你，来个大大的拥抱
再亲一个，宝贝！
-Thank you very much.
-Happy birthday.
太谢谢了
生日快乐
-Oh, thanks!
-Thank you.
噢，谢谢
谢谢你
-C'mon, me first!
-No, read the card first.
别抢，我先过来的
不嘛，先读这张卡
-Why?
-It's from both of us.
为什么啊？
是我俩一起写的啊
Okay. well, look, I don't know
if I’m going to be able to read this.
好吧，好吧，不过还不知道能不能读得成呢
My eyes aren't working too well at the
moment. How do you get these open?
我的眼睛在这个时间总是不太灵光。
怎么拆开啊？
-Oh, come on! Let's get to the present!
-Alright! Hang on, let's have a look.
噢，少来了，快打开！
好了，好了，别闹了，看一看。
He's out there
watering already.
他已经在外面开始浇水了
All he does is water.
他就知道浇水。
-Does he water all day?
-No.
他一整天都在浇水吗？
不。
He's a fat, fuckin' hairy...
他可真肥，还他妈这么多毛。。。
...watering garden gnome.
-What?
啧啧。。。这个园丁。
什么？
I said he's a fat, hairy,
fuckin' watering garden gnome.
我说他是个毛绒绒的肥园丁。
You were dead to the world
when I came in last night.
昨晚我回来的时候你睡得可真死
Are you on those
sleeping tablets again?
你是不是又开始吃安眠药了？
-Sometimes.
-Last night?
偶尔。
昨晚吃了吧？
I wish you'd try
without them.
我希望你能摆脱对这种药的依赖
I’m alright.
我没事。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Am I taking the kids to school?
我该送孩子们去上学了吧？
Alexandra? Am I taking
the kids to school today?
用我送孩子们去上学吗？Alexandra？
No, that's alright.
Jane's picking them up.
不用了，简会来接他们的
-Sam?
-Yep!
Sam?
干嘛
-Down here this instant!
-Coming!
快下来！
来了！
-Sammy, Sammy.
-Oh, my head!
Sammy, Sammy.
哎呀，我的脑袋啊
Buddy, are you okay?
Give us a look. where?
小伙子，没事吧？
让我看看撞哪儿了？
what happened?
怎么了？
Oh, he fell into the doorjamb.
He's all right. Alex?
哦，他撞门框上了
没事的，Alex?
-It hurts!
-He's alright.
好疼啊！
没事的
-Aren't you, little buddy?
-It hurts!
没事吧？小家伙？
很疼啊！
Yeah, I know.
Look at that dent in the wall!
是的，我知道
你看墙都被你撞了个坑。
-A couple of bills. Happy birthday.
-Thanks.
两张帐单，生日快乐。
谢谢
The phone's overdue.
电话欠费了。
I don't know why you don't
let me do the bill paying.
我就不明白为什么你不让我来付账呢
Yeah, I'll do it.
哦，这种事还是交给我来做吧。
-Hey, dad.
-Hey, princess.
嘿，老爸
嘿，小公主。
-Done your teeth?
-Yeah.
刷完牙了？是的。
well, don't come out here
when I’m smoking.
哦，我抽烟呢，你最好别在这。
Don't smoke.
那你就别抽呗
It’s my birthday.
I’ll smoke if I want to.
今天是我生日啊，我就放纵一下
what, like someone on death row
before they die forever?
怎么，你要像囚犯急着赴刑场一样啊？
-Is that better?
-Yep, that's better.
这样你高兴了吧？
是啊，高兴了。
Now we're gonna brush
our teeth, then.
好了，刷牙去吧。
-Yeah, I’ll do it.
-''Yeah, I’ll do it''.
好了，我这就去
好了，我这就去。
-What's in there that's so secret?
-Nothing.
那里有什么，搞得这么神秘？
没什么。
It’s a surprise.
是一个惊喜。
You'll get the rest
of your birthday present tonight.
今晚你会得到你剩下的生日礼物。
I’ll look forward to it.
我快等不及了。
-I couldn't have a sneak preview?
-Tonight.
能不能先让我偷偷看一眼？
晚上。
Okay.
好吧
Gotta go.
得走了。
See you tonight.
晚上见。
Oh, that's a great hug, tiger. You have
a great day and I’ll see you tonight.
哦，来个大大的拥抱，小老虎，
你会有完美的一天，我们晚上见。
Bye, dad. See you.
再见，老爸
You too, treasure. You have a lovely
day. I’ll see you this evening.
你也是，宝贝，一天好心情，晚上见。
-You're not gonna be late, are you?
-No way! Not tonight!
你可别回来晚了
不会的，尤其今晚！
-See you, dad.
-Bye, dad.
再见，老爸
See you, kids.
再见，孩子们。
This is getting ridiculous.
这太可笑了。
we'll all burn to death
in here one day.
指不定哪天我们都会被烧死在这儿。
Deadlocks are for when you're out of
the house, not to lock yourself inside.
这种单闩锁出去的时候用，
可不要把自己锁在屋子里。
-Good day, Bill. How's the garden?
-Good, Steve. Growing.
早，Bill，花园怎么样？
不错，Steve.长得很好。
How's The Complete Home
Security Company?
"合家安保"公司怎么样？
It’s growing too.
也在壮大。
I’ll bet it is.
这还用你说
It works, eh?
很有效，啊？
Your house makes me
very proud.
在你家工作让我很有面子。
Okay.
听着。
There's a change of plan.
You're not going to school today.
计划有变，你们今天不用上学去了。
Yeah! Really?
哇，真的吗？
More of dad's birthday surprise?
是老爸生日的更多惊喜吗？
-That's naughty, mum.
-Isn't it?
好狡猾啊，老妈
是啊。
Okay, so come on,
out of those school uniforms!
好了，过来，现在把学生服脱下来吧！
-And hang them up!
-Alright!
挂起来！
好的。
-We've got out of school! Cool!
-No homework!
逃学了，太酷了，不写家族作业了。
No more homework for today.
今天不用写作业了。
-Morning, Steve.
-Good morning, Duncan.
早，Steve。
早上好，Duncan.
-Hi, Steve.
-Good day, beautiful.
嗨，Steve，
早啊，美人。
Sorry, kids.
不是有意的，孩子们。
Hello, Steve.
你好，Steve。
-Your appointments for this afternoon.
-Thanks, Chris.
这是你下午的预约。
谢谢，Chris。
Don't forget you can't use
the boardroom today.
哦，对了，你今天不能用会议室。
-Why not?
-Board meeting.
为什么？
今天有董事会。
Yeah, that's good.
嗯，这样很好
Here you go.
给你
Hold it still, Emma.
扶稳了，Emma。
It’s meant to be the same
as yesterday, isn't it?
这意味着和昨天是一样的，对吗？
-Well, it is.
-Good on you, Sam.
哦，是的
干得不错，Sam.
Here you go.
给。
-Are you okay, mum?
-Yeah. I’m just a bit sentimental.
你还好吧，妈妈？
哦，没什么，只是有点伤感。
where's mum?
妈妈呢？
Mum!
妈！
Go get her, will you?
去找找她，好吗？
Mum!
妈！
-Well?
-Door's closed.
怎样？
门关上了。
-My room's a mess.
-So?
我的房间好乱啊
那又怎样？
So it wasn't before
and it is now.
没怎么样，只是以前从来不会这样的
You are a reject.
你是个小废物。
No, no, no, backspace,
not return.
不，不，按退格键，别按回车。
why doesn't this bloody thing
do what I tell it to?
这些该死的怎么不按我说的做呢？
Steve, you're wanted
in the boardroom.
Steve，会议室有人找你。
Shit!
他妈的！
-Why ''shit''?
-That can only mean one thing:
为什么这样说？
这只意味着一件事：
promotion, demotion.
I’m fired or I’m retrenched.
升迁或降职，被炒或减薪。
well, that's four things.
哦，那不是四件事吗。
But only one of them's
acceptable to me.
但其中只有一件是我能接受的。
-Will you still talk to me afterwards?
-Steve.
稍候我们再继续谈？
Steve。
we might be a little while,
but I'd still like you to wait.
可能还有耽搁一会儿
你能等我们一下吗
At 40 cents a minute,
you can take as long as you like.
我会按每分钟40分钱计费，
你想耽搁多久就多久。
There's been another change
of plans. A big change.
计划还有一个改变，一个大改变。
Bye, mum. See ya!
再见，妈妈，回见！
Bye!
再见！
Bye.
再见
See ya!
Bye.
再见。
what the fuck?
Not another one!
搞毛啊搞？
又来一张！
You fuckin' little hairy
garden gnome!
这该死的多毛怪园丁！
No, no, no.
This is too much, Alexandra!
不，不，不，这太过份了。Alexandra!
Christine!
where have the photos
of my kids gone?
我孩子的照片哪儿去了？
-I couriered them to your wife.
-You what? why?
我快递给你太太了。
你什么？为什么啊？
It’s a surprise, Steve.
是个惊喜，Steve。
I’m ready.
我准备好了。
You're wanted
in the boardroom, Steve.
Steve，到会议室来一下。
That bloke from the bank's gonna
be here in less than five minutes.
银行的那个家伙五分钟内就来了
They said to come now.
可他们让你现在就过去。
-Happy birthday, Steve.
-Yeah, yeah.
生日快乐，Steve。
we've had that.
This one's different.
这一招用过了，还有什么别的花样吧
Is that all?
就这些吗？
Yes, that's all, Steve.
是的，就这些，Steve。
Come on, Alex,
pick up the phone!
快点啊，Alex，接电话啊！
Can I buy you a drink?
Double celebration.
请你喝一杯好吗？
双喜临门哦
No way. Absolutely have
to be home on time tonight.
不行啊，今晚必须准时回家。
Can't be late
for my own surprise party.
我自己的惊喜晚会可不能迟到的
what? Haven't been invited?
怎么？你没被邀请吗？
Geez, you're a good actor!
天，演得可真像
See you tonight!
晚上见
Let's party
Come on, it's gonna be a big party
来吧，来狂欢
在这美丽的夜晚
Hey baby, don't tell me no lies
This birthday party is a big surprise!
抛弃所有谎言
生日晚会上将有惊喜连连
Hey, Bill, what's happened?
Not watering tonight?
嘿，Bill，怎么了？
今晚不浇水了吗？
I don't know, I don't know...
不知道，我不知道。。。
I tell you, in this weather, those plants
are just going to shrivel up and die.
我和你讲啊，这种天气，
植物不浇水可是要枯萎的啊。
Surprise!
惊喜！
Shit.
搞什么鬼。
Anybody here?
有人吗？
Shit.
妈的。
Jesus!
天！
-Is it going now?
-Yep. It’s on.
开始了吗？
是的，开始了。
Going?
开始了？
Honey?
亲爱的？
-Emma! Over here! We're over here!
-I've nearly done it. Yes, I know.
Emma！过来！到这来
快弄完了，是的，我知道。
-Video us!
-You'd better hang on then!
给我们录像啊！
你最好别乱动！
-No, not yet.
-You got us? Yeah?
等会，还没好。
录到了吗？啊？
-No, not yet.
-Can you see me?
还没有。
能看到我吗？
-Gotcha!
-You right?
录到了！
还好吗？
-Hello, darling. Happy birthday.
-Happy birthday, dad!
嗨，亲爱的，生日快乐
生日快乐，老爸！
Yeah, yeah. Happy birthday.
Now tell me what's going on.
哦，哦，生日快乐
现在快点告诉我怎么回事。
Now, before we get
too far into this...
现在，在你还没迷糊之前。。。
I want you to go to the fridge
and get yourself a beer...
你可以到冰箱里拿一杯啤酒来喝
and then sit down and watch.
然后坐下来慢慢欣赏。
Go on.
去啊。
Put us on pause, get yourself a beer.
We'll still be here when you get back.
按下暂停，去拿杯啤酒
你回来后，我们还在这等你。
-Go on!
-Are we on pause now?
去吧！
我们现在暂停了吗？
Okay.
好吧。
Yes?
回来了？
I’ll assume you've paused
us before now...
我猜你之前一定暂停画面了吧
and that you're back
with your beer.
现在带着啤酒回来了。
-Emma? The drinks, darling.
-Can I have the blue one?
Emma，把饮料拿来，亲爱的
我要那个蓝色的行吗？
-Cheers!
-Cheers, dad!
干杯！
干杯，老爸！
-Cheers!
-Go on! Cheers!
干杯
来啊！干杯！
-Cheers!
干杯！干杯！
-Cheers, dad!
干杯！干杯老爸
-Cheers!
-Go on. Cheers!
干杯，来啊，干杯！
Cheers!
干杯！
-This is nice.
-Say goodbye to your father now.
不错
现在和你们的爸爸说再见吧。
I’m going to come up
with the adults only bit.
下面内容儿童不宜
Bye, dad. We hope you have
a happy birthday...
再见，老爸，祝你生日快乐！
and hope you like your presents
as much as we liked making it for you.
希望你和我们一样，喜欢我们为你精心准备的的礼物
Thanks, Emma.
谢谢你，Emma.
Bye, dad. We hope you liked your
birthday and you liked your presents...
再见，老爸，希望你生日快乐并喜欢你的礼物
-As much as we...
-...as much as we liked...
和我们
我和们一样喜欢
...making it for you.
-Thanks, Sam.
为你精心准备的
谢谢你，Sam。
-Bye, dad. See you.
-Bye.
再见，老爸
再见。
They've gone.
他们走了！
Steve, I decided a different
sort of birthday present...
Steve，我决定今年为你送上一个
was in order this year.
绝对特别的生日礼物
So here it is.
要开始了。
The tape machine!
Just hold on a minute.
录像机
稍等片刻。
It’s a pity I don't know how
the camera remote works...
抱歉，这摄像机遥控操作我不太会用。。。
or this'd be smoother.
这样会好些了
Right. Your present.
好了，礼物马上送上。
Fuck!
妈的！
I’m not very good at this,
but I’ll try my best.
我不太在行，但我会尽我所能
Alex...
The...?
这。。。
where has this come from?
哪儿来的这主意啊？
I didn't time that
very well, did l?
哦，我好像没算好时间
what are you doing?
Don't stop! Turn it back on!
搞什么？
别停，接着来啊！
I’m still here, Steve.
我还在这儿，Steve。
-I’m just thinking about what to do.
-Well, turn it back on!
我在想该怎么做
哦，接着跳啊！
No, I can never think
with you watching me.
不了，一想到你在看我就难为情。
Should I rewind the
music and continue?
要我把音乐带倒回去，接着来吗？
Yes! Yes! Rewind the tape!
是啊，是啊，快倒带！
I can't think, 'cos I know
you'll be listening.
我都快不能思考了，因为我知道你一直在听着
And I hope you're
not laughing at me.
而且我希望你没有笑话我。
Oh, come on, Alex!
哦，怎么会呢，Alex！
Rewind the tape!
倒带！
No, I don't think
I’ll rewind the music yet.
不了，我还是觉得先别倒回去了
Let's talk for a minute, first.
我们先聊会吧！
Now, just a moment.
现在，就一会儿。
It’s our wedding photo, Steve.
这是我们的结婚照片，Steve。
I just wanted to show you
that before we started.
我只是想在开始前让你先看看这个
First of all,
I want to thank you for being...
首先，我要感谢你无论用什么标准衡量。。。
by most definitions, such a good
father and provider.
你都是一个会养家的好爸爸。
The kids love you,
and you love them.
孩子们爱你，当然你也爱他们。
And you do try your best with them.
I see that and I recognize that.
你为他们做了一个父亲该做的一切
我看得到，也清楚得很
Thank you.
谢谢你。
They're good kids,
aren't they?
他们是好孩子，不是吗？
If there's one thing we've sort
of done right it's the kids.
如果说只有一件事我们还算做得好的
那就是我们拥有这么好的孩子了。
But it's not enough, Steve.
但这怎么够呢？Steve.
''Good kids'' is not enough.
仅仅有双好儿女是不够的
You can hardly fail to have noticed
that I’m not very happy.
你可能都没意识到吧
我根本不快乐。
-That's an understatement.
-That's an understatement, really.
这说不过去。
事实上，这说不过去。
The truth is I’m actually
very unhappy.
事实上，我真的非常不快乐。
I’m feeling a bit cold.
我觉得有点冷
I never used to be unhappy so I must
have a lot to be unhappy about.
我从前也挺快乐的，所以我现在不快乐，
一定有很多不快乐的理由。
Darling, I’ve heard
all this before.
亲爱的，这些我都听你说过
There's nothing going on here
that a little Prozac wouldn't fix.
就这点事，来一片“百忧解”就搞定了
Or some effort
at helping yourself.
或者自己调整一下
Happy birthday.
生日快乐。
Jesus!
天哪！
...and I know you're a
consummate liar, Steve.
我知道你是个圆谎高手，Steve。
So don't think I don't know you
get a bit on the side.
所以别以为我不知道
你一直背着我在外面乱搞
Who is she, Steve?
她是谁，Steve？
Or more politely,
who are they?
或者不只一个，她们都是谁？
You've run my life
into the ground, Steve.
你让我的生活像坨屎
And what have I got?
No choices.
看看我还有什么？
没有选择
No rights.
没有权利。
No money other than what
you make me beg for.
用钱还得可怜巴巴向你要
I’ve got nothing!
我一无所有！
Not even me!
甚至没有了我自己
I don't exist!
我根本不存在！
So I may as well
not exist!
所以说我是不存在的
Not loaded.
子弹没上膛。
More's the pity.
太遗憾了。
Now just give me a minute.
等我一分钟
But keep watching. There's some
really good bits coming up.
别走开，接下来保证更精彩
Jesus Christ!
天哪！
Being a bit rough on you,
aren't l?
有点难接受，啊？
Getting a bit tight.
有一点紧。
Must be a size too small.
一定是号码太小了
That's better.
Isn’t it, Steve?
这样好些了，是吗，Steve？
Get the blood circulating
a bit better.
血液循环好些了。
I have to look after them...
我得好好呵护它。。。
they're one of the few
assets I have, aren't they?
它是我为数不多的资本了，不是吗？
But unfortunately they're not.
但很不幸，它不是
They're not an asset, Steve,
they're liability.
它不是一个资本，Steve，
相反，它是债。
The thing I’ve been leading
to with all this...
导致我所做的这些。。。
and please forgive
my erratic behavior...
并希望你原谅我的疯狂举动的。。。
is that three days ago...
是三天前的一份。。。
this biopsy confirmed...
活检结果。。。
that I have breast cancer.
我得了乳腺癌。
Left breast is absolutely riddled.
癌细胞已遍布左乳房了
Right breast on the way.
右边的也快了
It’s already in my lymph nodes.
淋巴结上都有了
I left it too late.
I was scared.
发现得太晚了，我很害怕。
I’m a mess, as you can see.
正如你所看到的，我现在一团糟
I have a 50-50 chance
of surviving it.
我有五成机会活下来。
My breasts have no chance.
我的乳房却没机会了。
You'd better take
a good look at them now...
你最好现在好好端详一下它。。。
because they're
coming off next week.
因为下星期它就没了。
Both of them.
两个都没了
A double radical mastectomy.
双乳根制性切除手术。
I’m scared, Stevie.
我很害怕，Stevie。
I tried to tell you,
but I didn't know where to begin.
我试过要告诉你，只是不知道从何说起。
But I’m being brave about it.
现在我有这个勇气了。
I’ll send the kids away for a few
weeks, Jane will look after them.
我把孩子送走几个星期，Jane会照看他们。
We'll see what happens.
我们看看接下来怎么办。
Will you come and visit me,
Steve, in the hospital?
Steve，我住院时，你会来探望我吗？
You won't want to see me
without breasts, will you?
你不会愿意见到没有乳房的我吧？
你愿意吗？
I won't be a real woman anymore.
我将不再是个真正的女人了。
Steve! I’m cured!
Steve！我痊愈了
Look! No biopsy, no cancer!
快看，哪有什么活检，哪有什么癌症!
They're almost as good
as they ever were!
这对宝贝还和以前一样美妙。
Had you going then, didn't l?
Hope you can take a joke.
骗到你了，是吧？
你不会开不起玩笑吧？
But, you know,
it does make me think...
但是，你知道
它确实让我思考了一些事情。。。
maybe I should have
a breast makeover.
我觉得我早该做做美乳了
Jesus, you are sick!
You are fucking sick!
天哪，你有病啊
你他妈的有病啊！
...makeover?
美乳？
Bigger. Silicone?
丰胸，硅填充？
No, I don't think so.
''More than a handful's a waste.''
Isn’t that what you say?
撑得住满手就够大了。
你肯定会这样说
Have them lifted.
我是要让它们更挺一些
They stand up quite well,
don't you think?
其实现在也还算挺吧？你说呢？
I know! Maybe I should have
my nipples pierced.
哦，我知道了，我也许该穿个乳环。
Would you like that?
Pierced nipples? Yes?
你喜欢吗？乳环？喜不喜欢？
Well, that's even something
I could do myself.
干这件事我自己来就行
In fact, I could do it now
so you can watch.
事实上我现在就可以穿，敬请欣赏！
Found one and I’ve burnt the end of
it already so you wouldn't have...
我找到了一个，一端已经用火烤过了，
所以你不用。。。
to sit through the boring bit.
Considerate, aren't l?
无聊地一直等。
看我想得多周到，是不是？
Now, let's see...
see if I’m brave enough to do it.
好了，接下来看一看。。。
看看我是不是有勇气穿这个环。
I think...
I think they stick it in the side.
我觉得。。。
我觉得好像卡在里面了。
I think I have to push harder.
看来我要更用点力来扎了。
There's blood here, Steve.
哦，Steve，你看这出血了。
I don't know if you can see it,
but there's blood.
不知道你能不能看清楚
但这儿出血了
Can you see it?
你能看到吗？
I don't know how anyone
can do it.
为什么别人就能做到呢？
-Not yet.
-What the fuck...?!
先别。
这他妈怎么回事。。。
Ignore that, honey.
It wasn't meant to happen.
别理会那只手，亲爱的
这一幕本不该出现的
Ignore it?
How the fuck can I ignore that?
不理会？
我他妈怎么能不理会？
That's him.
是他。
It’s that fucking hairy-handed,
watering garden gnome!
是那狗娘养的多毛怪园丁的爪子。
I don't know how anyone
can do it.
为什么别人就能做到呢？
-Not yet!
-Shut up...
先别！
闭嘴。。。
Ignore that, honey.
It wasn't meant to happen.
别理会那只手，亲爱的
这一幕本不该出现的
Shut up.
闭嘴。
Right.
好了
That's it.
This is enough!
就这样吧
够了！
Enough is enough!
别太过份了！
You bastard!
混蛋！
Fuck!
操
我操
This is not funny, Alex.
别和我开这种玩笑，Alex.
Fuck!
操
I can hardly go outside
and have one, can l?
我是不是都出不去了？
I wonder what other tricks
you've got hidden away...
你还能想出什么鬼把戏。。。
in that sick little
mind of yours.
就凭你那点小智商
Ignore that, honey.
It wasn't meant to happen.
别理会那只手，亲爱的
这一幕本不该出现的
That was not meant to happen.
那一幕不是故意出现的。
Perhaps we'd better forget
about the nipple piercing...
也许，我们应该把穿乳环的事放一边
and get down to serious business.
谈点正经事
I hope you're still watching.
我希望你还在观看着。
You remember our
wedding night, Steve?
还记得我们的新婚之夜吗，Steve？
I do.
反正我是记得的
Almost every minute of it.
几乎记得每一个细节。
You wanted me.
You needed me.
你是那么的需要我，爱着我
You touched me everywhere.
你抚摸我身体的每寸肌肤
Even in my heart.
甚至我的心。
And the next morning
it was the same.
第二天早上，你依然不倦不休。
You didn't let me
get dressed the whole day.
你一整天都不让我穿衣服。
You wanted nothing but me.
除了我，你什么都不想要
You made me feel so special.
你让我觉得自己如此特别。
And that night...
到了晚上
And it was even more adventurous.
我们尝试更大胆的
And then the next day you still
didn't want us to get dressed.
再接下来的第二天，
你还是性致勃发，不愿意穿衣服
You wanted to see
my naked body always.
你无时无刻都想要看我赤裸的身体。
To feel it on and on.
让情欲激荡
To touch it
and to explore it...
抚摸它，探索它
and pleasure it.
让它快乐
And the next day...
and the next...
一天，一天，再一天。。。
until I realized
it had nothing to do with me.
我终于意识到，你迷恋的并不是我
That it was just between
you and my body.
你迷恋的只是我的身体。
You hadn't married me,
you'd married my body.
你娶的不是我，你娶的是我的身体。
You didn't need me,
you only needed my body.
你需要的也不是我
你需要的是我的身体。
Isn’t that right?
我说得没错吧？
And then, only weeks later...
然后，也就是几个星期后。。。
before I could do anything l
discovered I was pregnant with Emma.
还没来得及做些什么别的事情，
我就发现我怀上了Emma。
Then what could I do?
那我还能干什么呢？
It’s a long time since you made
them talk to each other, Steve.
你已经很久没让它们互相交谈了，Steve。
''Hi. I’m Alexandra.''
''嗨. 我是Alexandra.''
''Hi. I’m Steve.''
嗨，我是Steve。
Do you have any idea how
I felt whenever you did that?
你知道每次你这么做的时候我是怎么想的？
I don't suppose you do.
我并不想你那样做
I felt like a cow.
那让我觉得自己像头奶牛
I felt like
a mother ape in a zoo!
我觉得自己像
一只动物园里的猴妈妈。
It wasn't like that.
不是这样的。
That's our marriage, Steve.
You and my naked body.
这就是我们的婚姻，Steve.
你和我赤裸的身体
And as long as I gave you
access to my body...
只我要一直用我的身体曲意奉迎
you were satisfied that
the marriage was going well.
你就会对我们的婚姻状况心满意足。
And you were content to give lip
service to all those other things...
然后你会对很多其它的事情乱开空头支票
that are supposed to be part
of a marriage...
而那些本来应该是婚姻的重要组成部分。
like affection and respect,
and mutual support, and togetherness...
比如情感，比如尊重，比如相互间的支持
比如那种相濡以沫
''Togetherness''!
相濡以沫！
You think togetherness is both of us
naked in the same bed...
你以为相濡以沫就是两人赤身露体地
睡在同一张床吗？
while you grope my tits and ass
and finger my cunt!
就是你摸奶捏臀抠逼吗？
Groping is easy, Steve.
Anyone can do it.
这些还不简单，Steve。
是个人都会做。
Okay, that's enough.
That's enough.
好了，可以了，可以了。
Sorry, Steve.
I got a bit carried away there.
对不起，Steve。
我有点失态了。
I think you should look
carefully now, Steve.
Steve，你现在可得要看仔细了
Pay attention.
眼睛瞪大点
Because I’m going to take
my panties off...
因为，我要褪去短裤了。。。
and you know where
that usually leads us.
这个动作会让我们接下来做什么
你是一清二楚的
See, Steve?
看到了吗？Steve。
My naked body.
我的裸体。
The body you used
to love so much.
让你曾经爱得不能自持的裸体。
The body you're still married to,
for better or for worse.
不管好坏，还是和你结了婚的那具裸体。
a little the worse since
the kids. But still your body.
生了孩子之后有点走样，
但毕竟还是属于你的身体
Take a good look at it.
一定好好看看。
You'll be able
to look at this body...
你会从这部录像带中
this tape, again and again.
一次一次地看到这个身体
So...
那么。。。
Right down to nothing.
Nothing hidden anymore.
全脱光光了，一览无余。
Time to talk about
''the tunnel of love''.
是时候谈一谈“爱之穴”了
Hard for me to call it
anything else after all this time.
经历了这些后，让我把它叫成别的
还真是太为难我了
It’s precious to me, Steve.
它可是我的珍宝，Steve。
It’s private.
我的私隐。
It’s mine.
真正属于我的啊
So what do you do?
那么你是怎么做的呢？
At first you just look for opportunities
to stick that thing of yours in.
开始，你寻找一切机会
把你的那话儿插到里面
That's what you do, Steve, you stick
it in and move it round a bit...
你就是这么干的，插进去，再一点点移动。。。
at every available opportunity.
寻找一切可乘之机
And then when there aren't
enough opportunities...
而当机会不太好，无法。。。
to satisfy your endless need,
you begin to pressure me.
满足你无止境的需求时
你便开始给我施压
Never so much
as to be offensive.
无冒犯之意
You're too smart for that.
你太精于此道了
But a constant pressure.
你不断地给我施压
Always knocking on the door,
asking to come in.
总是敲敲门就想进入
Never waiting to be invited in.
从来都是迫不及待
Then comes the finger.
接着你的手指也按捺不住了
The finger that's like an octopus
that suddenly manages...
像八爪鱼一样，想方设法地想要。。。
to find its way into the
''tunnel of love''...
找到通往“爱之穴”的路径
at the most unexpected moments...
而此时往往都是我最不想要的时候
when maybe all I’m wanting
is some affection...
或许那时我更需要的是一些情感慰藉。。。
or I’m in the shower and suddenly
you're in there too...
不管是我在洗澡，或者在洗碗
with your finger, or I’m
at the sink washing up...
你总是不期然的带着你的八爪鱼
无休无止
and suddenly you come up
behind me and there's the finger.
你总是突然的出现，大施五指神功
Why do you think I never wear
skirts or dresses anymore?
我要是永远不穿裙子或衣物，会美死你吧。
Worse is when I’m asleep and l
wake up to find your finger inside me.
最糟的是，一觉醒来，
发现你的手指头竟然在我身体里
Sneakily trying
to get me excited...
鬼鬼祟祟地在挑逗我的情欲
so that you can stick your thing
in and move it round a bit.
这样才好方便你泄欲。
Then, Steve, there's this:
然后，Steve，还有这个：
you smuggle one of these
into bed with us...
你偷偷带到床上来的。。。
and when I’m ready to receive
you into my ''tunnel of love''...
当我真正准备好接纳你进入“爱之穴”时
you insert the cucumber,
pretending it's you.
你却在那时插了要黄瓜
还假装那是你
The cucumber was
a turning point, Steve.
黄瓜事件是个转折点，Steve。
Because I realized how far gone
you were, how obsessed.
因为我意识到你有多离谱了，
意识到你神经错乱到了何种地步。
Did you select the right
sized one at the supermarket...
在超市里买这根黄瓜的时候，
你确定大小合适了吗？
knowing what you were
going to be doing with it?
你想好了要用它来做什么吗？
And when you paid for it, did you
think about sticking it up the cashier?
付款时，你动没动过念头
要把它插到收银员的身体里？
How many previous nights
had you smuggled it into bed...
之前你有多少夜晚偷偷把它带到床上。。。
hoping to be able to use it?
希望能用上它？
What goes on in that mind of yours...
你脑袋里到底哪根弦不对了。。。
to think it would be okay to
stick it in me without asking me?
让你觉得不经我同意，这么做也没问题的？
That's what I should have
done to you then.
我早就该这么做了
And that's the beauty of this video,
Steve. I can say what I want to say.
这就是录影的精彩之处，Steve，
我可以畅所欲言。
I can say the things
you never let me say.
可以说那些你永远都不让我说的
I can say them without being
interrupted or without being...
并且不被打扰，不会被说成
talked over the top of, without
being told I wouldn't know...
夸夸其谈，也不会被说成老生常谈。。。
or I have peculiar ideas.
更不会被说成无稽之谈
Then, finally, there's this:
接下来，最后一个，是它
Nice birthday present, Steve.
I really appreciated it.
很棒的生日礼物，Steve。
我可真是要感谢你。
''What did you get
for your birthday, mum?''
“妈妈，你收到了什么生日礼物”
''Oh, a vibrator, darling.''
“噢，亲爱的，是一个自慰振动棒。”
''Your father's trying
to improve our sex lives...
“你老爸想提高我们性生活质量。。。
but he wouldn't have a clue.''
但显然他不得要领”
Do you know what this is, Steve?
你知道这是什么吗？Steve。
I’ll tell you what this is.
This is a machine.
我来告诉你
这就是一个器械。
It’s a machine you bought to go inside
me so that you can get your rocks off.
这只不过是你用来垦荒的掘土机。
Don't say it was for me
because it wasn't.
别说这是给我的
因为它不是
If I wanted one I would have
bought myself one long ago.
如果我需要，我老早就给自己买一个了。
What does this thing make me
in your eyes? Just another machine.
在你眼中，这东西把我变成了什么？
把我变成了另一个器械。
You can stick this up your ass
if it gives you so much pleasure!
如果它能带给你这么多乐趣，
为什么不把它插到你自己的菊花里。
Who are you, Steve?
我都不认识你了，Steve。
How can you need this part of me
and not this part. Not me?
你怎么能只需要这部分的我
而不是这部分
But I’ve learnt
from you, Steve.
但你可真是让我长了见识，Steve
I don't need you anymore.
我再也不需要你了
See? I’m doing it myself.
看到没？我自己也玩得很哈皮。
I don't need any part of you.
你的任何部分我都不需要。
I don't even need your money.
甚至不需要你的儿
I’ve made some money of my own.
我自己也赚了些钱
Yes, really!
真的，没骗你！
Don't you ever wonder
what I do all day?
你就没想过我一整天在家都干些什么？
When the kids are at school,
day after day?
日复一日，那些孩子们在学校的白天里
I’ll tell you what I do.
我来告诉你吧
I make money.
我在赚钱。
And I’ll show you how.
我会告诉你我怎么赚钱的
I’m ready.
我准备好了。
Don't.
不。
Don't do this.
不要这样。
This is how I’ve made
my money, Steve.
这就是我赚钱的方法，Steve。
Although this one's free,
for services rendered.
哦，当然这次是免费的
就当一次服务补偿好了
Don't do this!
不要这么做！
It’s my choice, Steve.
That's the difference.
这是我自己的选择，Steve
所以这不一样的。
I’m going to kill you.
我要宰了你。
We'd better do it again, Steve.
Better go on.
最好再来一次，Steve
最好继续。
Can never have too much
of a good thing, can we?
好东西永远不嫌多，不是吗？
Same again?
还来同样的吗？
Or something different?
或者换一种口味？
You want to see me ''cop that up the
ass'', as you so delicately put it?
你想要观看“菊花坐台”吗？
你不是想了很久吗？
''I’d like to see that bastard next
door cop it up the ass some day.''
我真TM想看到隔壁那王八蛋哪天被人
把菊花干个底朝天。
Isn’t that what you say?
你是这样说的吗？
Well, here's your chance to see that
bastard next door give it up the ass.
好了，正好有这个机会你能看到了
隔壁那王八蛋屁股正翘老高等着呢。
No?
不要？
What's the matter?
为什么啊？
Don't you like
your birthday present?
你不喜欢这个生日礼物吗？
Alex...
My name is Alexandra.
我名字叫Alexandra。
what?
什么？
How many times do I have
to say? I hate Alex.
我得要和你说多少次
我恨Alex这个名字。
I hate it when you call me that.
I have a name. It’s Alexandra.
尤其讨厌你叫我“Alex”
This is the tricky part, Steve.
这部分该让你抓狂了，Steve。
what?
什么？
This is where you discover
the remote doesn't work anymore.
在这部分里，你会发现遥控器不好用了。
well, you're here, but...
but I rewound you.
哦？还有图像，但
但我已经倒带了啊。
I paused you.
也按了暂停了。
It’s one of life's
mysteries, Steve.
生活是神奇的，Steve。
You're mad.
you're completely mad.
你疯了
你完全疯了。
Yes, I’m mad, but not
in the way you think.
是，我是疯了，但可不是你想的那种。
Remember that bullet you received
in your mobile phone?
还记得你手机里收到的那颗子弹吗？
There's another just like it
pointed at you this very moment.
还有一颗一模一样的子弹
就在此刻正瞄准着你。
So be a good boy and
sit down in your armchair.
所以，还是做个好孩子
乖乖地坐回到椅子去
Do it, Steve.
照我说的做，Steve。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I just want to finish this
the way I planned it.
我只想按照我的计划结束这一切。
You need help, Alexandra.
You need treatment.
你需要帮助，Alexandra。
你需要治疗。
It’s always the first thought,
isn't it, when a woman...
第一反应永远是这样，对不对？
当一个女人。。。
takes action
against her husband?
采取行动来对抗她的丈夫时。
Now we come to the
best part of your birthday present:
现在让我们进入这份生日礼物中
最精彩的部分。
your final humiliation.
对你最终的羞辱。
Although this one needs to be pretty
good and permanent to make up...
尽管这部分应该更完美，并且好好整理一番
for the years that I went through.
我这些年所有的过往
This one's different to the one
you've just seen, Steve.
但这部分和你之前看的完全不同，Steve
That was pre-recorded.
This one's live!
刚才那个是事先录好的
现在这个是现场直播！
It'll all be happening right
in front of your eyes.
实实在在发生在你眼皮子底下的。
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Are you ready, Steve?
准备好了吗？Steve
What? Not playing talkies?
It’s alright by me.
怎么？玩沉默？
那也没关系。
You can go, then.
那你可以走。
You think I’m watching you,
don't you?
你一定以为我在看你，是吧？
Gotcha.
找到你了。
He's back!
He's back on the air!
他回来了！
他回到直播现场了！
You're back, Steve.
你回来了，Steve。
But I can't see you very well.
Are you watching?
但我看不清你，你在看吗？
No. I’m not watching.
不，我没看。
At least you're listening.
至少你听得到。
-Where are you?
-None of your business.
你在哪？
你管得着吗？
You're getting the hang of this
a little faster than I’d hoped.
你这窍门找得比我预想的要快
We're gonna have to cut it short.
好吧，那我们就简短些吧
Looks like you won't get the last
part of your birthday present.
看起来，你得不到这生日礼物的最后部分了
Good!
那才好！
In fact, you'll never get
another present from me again.
事实上，你永远不会再得到我的生日礼物了。
well, that makes me
very, very happy.
哦，那可再开心不过了
And well it might.
好吧，如你所愿。
What makes you so very happy,
Steve, is Emma and Sam.
Steve，让你如此开心的 ，是Emma和Sam。
-There you are.
-What about Emma and Sam?
哦，你出来了
Emma和Sam怎么了？
I’ve taken considerable
trouble, Steve...
我考虑周全了各种麻烦问题，Steve。。。
to eradicate them
from your life.
我要让他们从你的生活中彻底消失。
You'll never see them again.
你永远都不会再见到他们了。
Nor will you find
a single photograph of them.
你甚至找不到一张他们的照片。
I’ve taken every one.
我把所有照片都收走了。
Baby photos, recent photos...
婴儿时期的，最近的，所有的照片。。。
the photos from your office.
还有你办公室的。
Even the photos from your wallet.
甚至你钱夹里的照片。
There's nothing of them left
for you to ever see.
你再也看不到他们留下的任何东西。
Soon...
很快。。。
Emma and Sam will begin
to fade a little from your memory.
Emma和Sam就开始在你记忆里逐渐消失。
You'll start to forget little
details about them.
你会一点点遗忘所有关于他们的细节。
And one day, you won't even
be able to remember their faces.
然后有一天，你会发现，
你已经忘了他们长什么样。
And then your life will be
completely empty.
那时，你的生活会变得无比空虚。
I got promoted today.
我今天被晋升了。
Well, it's a pity Emma
and Sam will never know.
規遗憾，Emma和Sam永远不会知道了。
They'd have been proud of you.
要是知道，他们会以你为傲的。
But they'll soon enough
forget you too.
但是，他们也会在最短的时间忘记你的。
what have I done to deserve this?
我做了什么让你如此待我？
I’ll tell you what
you've done, Steve.
我来告诉你，你做了什么，Steve。
You've constantly made me feel
the way you do now!
你把你现在这种糟糕的感觉，
一刻不停的施加于我。
I thought we had an okay marriage.
Not perfect, but okay.
我觉得我们的婚姻说得过去啊
虽然不尽善尽美，但也没什么问题啊。
I mean, you love me,
we both love the kids.
我是说，你爱我
我们也都爱咱们的孩子
where are the kids?
孩子们在哪儿？
Oh, my taxi has arrived.
哦，我叫的出租车来了。
This is goodbye, Steve.
该说再见了，Steve。
You can't touch me.
你摸不到我
You'll never find me.
你也不会找到了
I’ll be somewhere far,
far away...
我会在一个离你很远很远的地方。。。
with the children.
和孩子们一起。
I hope you have a happy life
with yourself.
希望您老一个人也能幸福生活。
No.
不。
No, don't do this!
不要，别这样对我！
Happy birthday, Steve.
生日快乐！Steve。
I have a license to use
this on intruders.
对于私闯者，我有用枪许可。
In my line of business it pays
to be friendly with the cops.
在我的行当里，和警察关系打理得也不错
Please, Steve...
请吧，Steve...
...make yourself comfortable.
-Where's Alexandra?
不要拘束。
Alexandra在哪儿？
She's gone, my friend.
她离开了，朋友。
Gone.
离开了。
Sit down, please.
请坐吧。
Have this one.
来一杯。
And we'll have another one later,
after I call the police.
等我给警察打完电话，再来一杯
Duty officer, please.
麻烦，找一下值勤人员。
You've had a bad day.
Have another one.
你这一天够糟糕的
再来一杯吧。
who's that?
哪位？
Ah, Rob. How are you?
It’s Bill. Bill Con.
啊，Rob，你好吗？我是Bill。Bill Con。
Listen, I’ve got a bloke bailed up
here. He broke into my house.
是这样的，有个家伙闯到我房间来了，
他已经被我制服了。
well, he smashed his way in...
哦，他是破墙而入的。。。
with an idea of doing
some damage to my person.
对我的人有可能会有威胁。
Very funny, really.
很好笑，确实。
No, no, no.
I’m not going to press any charges.
不，不，不
我不会提出指控。
He's understandably a little
bit drunk and a lot upset.
他只是有点醉，又有点不安
但基本上还算清醒。
well, just come over here when
you have time. Pick him up.
嗯，有时间的时候，过来一趟
把他带走就行了。
Hold him overnight
and cool him down a bit.
押他一晚上，让他冷静冷静。
when you're ready.
Thank you, Rob. Bye.
方便的时候。
谢谢，Rob，再见。
He thought it was very funny...
他觉得很好笑。。。
that The Complete Home
Security Company was broken in.
“合家安保公司”设施竟然形同虚设。
Ah, these cops!
They've got a sense of humor.
啊，那些条子！
他们真有幽默感。
Probably you neglected
to bring your own.
你可能没带吧（烟）
You look like shit.
你看上去糟透了。
I feel really sorry
for you, Steve.
真为你遗憾，Steve。
You are going to suffer
for a while.
可够你受一段时间的了。
She's a very intelligent woman.
她是个非常聪明的女人。
Your wife.
你老婆。
Very clever.
非常聪明。
She's not as smart
as she thinks she is.
她没有她自己想像的那么聪明。
I’ve got the tape.
我得到了录影带
Oh yes, you are meant to have it.
是啊，你打算拥有它。
I’ve got the kids.
我就有了我的孩子。
She forgot the kids
were on the tape.
她忘了录影带上也有孩子们。
I’ve still got them.
我还能看到他们。
well, I’m really sorry, but...
噢，真抱歉，但是。。。
when you locked up I must go
to your place and...
当警察带走你后，我必须进你房间。。。
erase them.
把录影带抹掉。
That's the final part
of my contract.
这是我和你老婆的协议中最后的一部分。
She thought of everything.
她想周全了所有事情。
She's a great woman.
她真是太了不起了。
She's mad.
她疯了。
Crazy.
是个疯子。
Some years ago
my wife left me...
多年前，我老婆也离开了我。。。
and I was certain
that she was mad.
我也想当然觉得她疯了。
There was no doubt about it.
而且是毋庸置疑的。
But then later I met her and
I understood that she was not.
但后来，我再次遇到她是
我明白了，她没疯
For it was I who caused her
to be that way.
她变成那样，完全是我的原因。
She was not mad.
她没疯。
I drove her mad,
but she was not mad.
是我逼得她发疯
但她根本没疯
It’s a funny thing.
真的很好笑
It’s time to go.
是时候离开了。
wait a minute!
等一下！
Let's go.
走吧
Come on.
过来。
I’ll tell you what I’ll do for you.
我会为你做点事，
She will never know this.
不会让你老婆知道的。
I’ll leave a little bit
of your kids on the tape.
我会在录影带里保留一点你的孩子影像。
You'd do that for me?
你会为我这么做？
Just a little bit.
就短短的一点
-Thank you.
-That's okay.
谢谢你　　没关系
By the way, come and visit me
when they let you go.
另外，出来后欢迎你前来拜访
I’ll give you your new keys.
我会给你把新钥匙。
After all, you paid for them.
毕竟，是你付帐的。
Shit!
妈的！
Is Alexandra in?
Alexandra在吗？（这人是嫖客？）
Mistress Alexandra?
Alexandra小姐？
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。
-Cheers, dad!
-Cheers.
干杯，老爸　　　　干杯。